Hello everyone and welcome back to English
Pod. My name is Marco and my name is
Catherine so Marco what we're talking
about here today. Today we're going
shopping again. Mmm we go shopping
a lot here in English 5 but this is an
upper-entry media level lesson so we've got
some very specific terminology to cover.
Exactly we're going shopping for
a digital camera so we're gonna be
talking about very specific maybe
a little bit technical vocab related to
this very fascinating
and expensive product.
All right I'm very
excited I recently
purchased a camera but we won't talk
about that yet. Let's take a listen to the
dialogue for the first time
and when we come back we
can talk about some of
the really interesting details.
Hello ma'am can I help you find something?
Yes actually I'm looking to buy a camera.
We've got a wide selection. Do you
know if you'd like a point in shoot or
something a little fancier? Are you
shopping for yourself or for someone else?
Actually I'm buying a camera from my
husband. Ah well then I'd recommend a nice
entry-level digital SLR. Yeah can I
take a look at the SLRs you carry? Sure
thing follow me. This here is the look. The
Canon EOS yeah it's okay but I'm looking
for something that performs better and
low light has a better display panel and
longer battery life. Oh the Nikon D60 is
a nice option? Yeah but what kit lens does
this camera come with? I don't want
some bulky telephoto lens. Ah well this one
has the looks to
me like an 18 to 55
millimeter lens. Pretty
standard. Not like my
husband will be stalking celebrities or
anything. Ah so um can I interest you in
any accessories? Do you carry polarizing
filters? Polarizing filters. Um we we
should. I'm sorry man looks like we're
sold out. No you're not. There's some
right here. Oh well would you look at that
polarizing filters? Thanks for your help.
Ralph? No problem man. All right we're
back so apparently this girl knew more
than the salesman
about this uh these things.
Is this from a real
life experience?
Maybe. Well we can get to that
later like I said but there are some very
important words that anyone who wants
to buy a camera should know before they
go into the store and these are coming
across the board. So let's take a look
at these in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right so in
language takeaway today we have our first
difference. Now it's very important to
know the difference between point
and shoot camera and the digital SLR.
Okay so digital everyone knows digital now
right. That's the kind of photography we
have you don't use film. Okay use the
memory card to record digital images but
point and shoot are those little
cameras where you just click and it takes a
picture. There's no lens, there's no
additional lens, there's no special add-ons.
It's a small rectangle and you just
take normal pictures and that's the kind
of camera that like my mom uses and
everyone you have it in my purse and
whatever it's easy to use. But the
digital SLR is a kind of camera that's like
the old SLR where you have an like an
attachment of a you have a body and you
have a lens and they're just much fancier
and you have to do a lot more on your
own to make a nice picture. Now SLR that's
an acronym do you know what it stands
for? So an SLR is a single lens reflex
camera and that means that there's a lot
more you have to do as the photographer
to make sure that the picture comes
out well. Right so it's really interesting
because you can actually play with
the lens like the focus and you know
how much light you want to allow it to go
in and there's a lot of really you know
sometimes a little bit difficult things
that not many people understand.
Exactly and so I think that's why it's good
to do some research before you buy
one because there's so many differences
across the different cameras. Okay
now both on digital SLRs and on point and
shoot cameras you have something
that's called the display panel.
That's right so display panel is usually
covered in plastic and it's the area that
tells you how many pictures you've
taken how many pictures you can take if the
flash is on if you're doing an
automatic setting. So it's like the little
computer monitor that tells you what's
going on with the camera. Usually after
you take a picture you can also see
how it came out right in that moment.
Exactly and so a lot of times with these
fancy cameras you want to know if the
how big the display panel is and
how good the quality is in the display
panel because obviously if you take
a picture and it shows up bad in the
display panel you want to take a new
one but what if it's a display panel that's
broken? Right right okay very good
and that's actually one of the great
advantages of digital cameras that you can
actually see how your picture looks like.
Exactly in that moment. Instinct
gratification nice. All right now when she
was looking to buy this digital SLR she
mentioned something about a kit lens
okay this is fancy camera terminology
right because if you buy a point in
shoot there's no lens it's just the
camera but if you're buying a fancy
digital SLR you can buy the body which
means the the machine but there's no lens.
So normally people will sell
stores will sell cameras with a kit lens
that means they make a kit or they
make a combination for you. So it's the
body and the lens. Exactly. But if you
want you can buy the body and the lens
separate maybe you want to really
fancy lens. Exactly so what's the kind of
fancy lens we might buy? A telephoto lens.
Ooh so these are the really big
lenses for super close-up shots from
from a distance right so you think of maybe
professional photographers or photo
journalists who have these kind of lenses
they're big and they're bulky and
they're not for traveling. Usually you see
them in like sporting events right
they're on the side of the field and they
have these big white and they're
usually white lenses on their camera so you
can actually take a very close picture
of the action that's far away. Exactly
and it's really good for those kind of
things where you have action or we're
trying to get close-ups. And now if
one of these accessories that could go
well with a telephoto lens or
any digital SLR is a polarizing filter.
Okay so filter is something that takes
certain elements out of something else so we
can filter coffee for example and it
takes the coffee grounds out and leaves the
water. But in a camera a polarizing filter
is something we put on to the glass of
the lens to change the way that
light goes into the lens. Okay so in this
way you take a picture maybe
of a very sunny day and it will look
differently if you didn't have this filter.
Exactly and you can also have a
UV filter which does similar things
with UV rays in this in the sunlight and
these are just filters or things you
put on the camera and polarizing means
that you're splitting up right
the the kind of light that goes in.
Okay very good very technical terms and but
they're very useful especially if you're
looking to buy one of these cameras and
you're not very familiar with the terms.
But why don't we move on now to
some very interesting phrases that we
signed a dialogue on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right so on fluency builder our first
phrase today is entry level. What's an
entry level digital SLR? Okay well entry
level is something that we can use for
any kind of purchase. So any kind
of thing that we buy. In the case of a
camera an entry level is not for an
expert or professional. It's something for
someone who's buying one for the first
time. Like for beginners. For beginners.
So entry level is like entry beginning
starting. We can have an entry level job
where you don't need
training or experience.
Right and entry
level camera where
you don't need long experience with
fancy cameras. Or training to know how to
use it. Okay very good so that's an entry
level camera but as you mentioned we
can also use it for the job. An entry
level job position. All right what about
our second phrase. Okay so this one goes
with the telephoto lens right. She says
I don't need a telephoto lens. My husband
doesn't need a telephoto lens. It's not
like he's going to be stalking celebrities.
Okay so we have this verb here to stalk.
To stalk that means to follow someone
around. Okay. And to look at them
and to watch them and to not leave
them alone. Now as you mentioned this
because this is a very
very interesting and
closely associated topic
with photographers.
You know you have the paparazzi who
follow celebrities and they have these
big telephoto lens so they can take pictures
of celebrities without them knowing.
Exactly and so you imagine
someone in a tree with a big
telephoto lens taking a photo of someone
famous who's you know half a mile away
and stalking celebrities is something
that's a bad thing right. But it's very
often illegal I think. I think it's
illegal. All right and what about our last
phrase. Would you look at that? Well
he said it in a very surprised tone right
kind of like he didn't really
expect to find the polarizing filters.
Right so he's embarrassed okay. Would you
look at that means oh wow I'm surprised.
Right. All right so it's it's awkward
right so you could say Marco you got a
little bit of food on your shirt.
You've had it for like two hour. Oh my god
would you look at that up. It's really
embarrassing I got food. So this man this
man who works at the store he's embarrassed
because he didn't know something
he should know. Okay. So he says oh
would you look at that. How funny I didn't
see those. Now we can also maybe
use it in a sarcastic tone right if I tell
somebody can you bring me the my
my my glasses that are on the table no
like I can't find them. They're not here
and then I find them. Would you look at
that. Here they are right on your head the
whole time. That's my mom. Would you look
at that? I was wearing my glasses
the whole time. All right very good.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue
for the last time and we'll be back to talk
about digital SLRs. Hello man can I
help you find something. Yes actually I'm
looking to buy a camera. We've got a
wide selection. Do you know if you'd like a
point in shoot or something a little
fancier. Are you shopping for yourself or
for someone else? Actually I'm buying a
camera from my husband. Well then I'd
recommend a nice entry-level digital SLR.
Yeah can I take a look at the SLRs you
carry. Sure thing follow me. This here
is the Canon EOS. Yeah it's okay but I'm
looking for something that performs
better in low light has a better display
panel and longer battery life. Oh the
Nikon D60 is a nice option. Yeah but what
kit lens does this camera come with?
I don't want some bulky telephoto lens.
Ah well this one has the looks to
me like an 18 to 55 millimeter lens.
Please stand it all day. Not like my
husband will be stalking celebrities or
anything. So can I interest you in any
accessories? Do you carry polarizing filters?
All the rising filters. We should. I'm
sorry man looks like we're sold out.
No you're not. There's some right
here. Oh well would you look at that.
Polarizing filters.
Thanks for your help Ralph. No problem man.
All right we're back so you mentioned
you recently bought a digital SLR camera.
How's that working on? I'm loving
it. I have to actually train myself on
how to use it because I used to
have an old film camera that had it was
actually an icon as well and it's it's
different using a digital SLR. There's a
lot of things you can do that are
very fancy because you actually there's a
computer inside essentially so it's
I'm gonna use to it. And what about the
difference in pictures like from a
point-in-shoot to a digital SLR does it
really make a great difference?
Are you very happy with it? There is a big
difference and part of the difference
is that you can control every aspect of
the photo. Okay so my digital camera
was a small little cannon you know the
little what are they called the power
shoot? And it made it took great
pictures because you know these cameras
have amazing pixel quality right they
have like 7.1 megapixels or like
9.1 megapixels so the quality is
really good but everything looks the same.
If I have my digital camera my
digital SLR I can frame a shot and I can
focus on one person but make everyone
else blurry. I can really make more
artistic photos whereas the point-in-shoot
is great for parties and for just like
every day stuff. Now what about traveling?
You have a dilemma there right
because you visit very beautiful
places where you would love to to
take very nice pictures with a digital SLR
but at the same time the inconvenience
of it of actually because they're
pretty big all of them were pretty big.
So what would you go on that would you
use a point-in-shoot or the digital SLR?
Well that's a good question one of the
reasons that I picked the lens that I
did is because it's not immense but I
really want to be able to do some like
landscape photography and I travel a lot
so I think it's it's worthwhile to suck
it up and just take the camera because
otherwise why did you buy it right?
Yeah that's true. All right so an
interesting topic here on English
Pod and I'm sure a lot of our users
travel around like to take pictures
or maybe our experts on digital
photography so why don't you
come to the website English Pod.
com we'll see you there and
until next time bye everyone bye